Finding Aid for George William Moore papers, 1874-1941
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
George William Moore papers 1874-1941
Moore, George William, b. 1847.
1 oversize folder
3 oversized volumes
5 linear feet
07167 Aa 2; UAm
Detroit attorney and prominent member of the Michigan Democratic Party. Correspondence, 1874-1926, Miscellaneous, 1922-1941, and Moore & Moore Records, 1880-1939 and Ledgers, 1881-1934.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Material was donated to the library by Jasper L. Moore (donor no. 9964 ) in October 2007.
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
George William Moore was born in Romulus Michigan in 1847, the son of George Washington and Mary (Emory) Moore. He received his law degree from the University of Michigan and started his legal practice in 18721. He, along with his partner, George Whitney Moore, founded the law firm of Moore & Moore, focusing on civil law, where Moore practiced throughout his legal career. Due to the similarity of their names, Mssrs. Moore often used their middle names in both official and personal correspondence. He married Katherine M. DeMill in 1885, though they later divorced. Together, they had one daughter, Katherine Palmer.
Though George William Moore never stood for political office, he was a prominent member of the Michigan Democratic Party. He acted as a member of the State Central Committee, the ruling body of the Michigan arm of the party, and was a close associate of Daniel J. Campau, the Michigan Democratic State Chair. Through his political involvement Moore became associated with William Jennings Bryan, with whom he corresponded, and whom he supported in all of Bryan's presidential runs.
The George William Moore papers include correspondence, letterpress books, and other records of the law firm of Moore & Moore; scattered materials relating to his involvement in the Democratic Party of Michigan; and correspondence from family members living in Romulus, Michigan. The papers are divided into four series, Correspondence, 1874-1926, Miscellaneous, 1922-1941, Moore & Moore Records, 1880-1939, and Ledgers, 1884-1932.
Subjects:
Democratic Party (Mich.). State Central Committee.; Moore, George William, b. 1847.; Law firms--Michigan--Detroit.; Lawyers--Michigan--Detroit.; Moore & Moore.; Romulus (Mich.)
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Moore, George William, b. 1847.; May, Thomas, 1860-1927.
Contributors:
Bryan, William Jennings, 1860-1925.; Comstock, William Alfred, 1877-1949.; Couzens, James, 1872-1936.
Genre Terms:
Political cartoons.
- Correspondence
  The Correspondence series is divided into three subseries: Letterpress books, Correspondence by Date, and Correspondence A-Z. The Letterpress books consists of Moore's outgoing letters and memos and are related primarily to Moore's professional and political activities. The other two subseries contain correspondence received by Moore. The Correspondence by Date subseries contains primarily family letters, though there is also correspondence relating to his political activities, including letters from William Jennings Bryan. The Correspondence A-Z subseries contains correspondence related to Moore's professional activities.
  - Letterpress books
    - 1903-1907, 5 volumes (Box 1)
    - 1907-1912, 4 volumes (Box 2)
    - 1914-1920, 4 volumes (Box 3)
  - Correspondence by date
    - 1874-1926 undated, 4 folders (Box 4)
      (include letters from Williams Jennings Bryan, 1904, 1906, 1907)
  - Correspondence (alphabetical)
    - A-Y, 5 folders (Box 4)
      (include letters from Senator James Couzens and William A. Comstock)
- Moore & Moore law firm records
  The Moore & Moore Records contain business and financial records of the law firm Moore & Moore. These records include correspondence, case files, and financial records and ledgers.
  - Business records and correspondence 1880-1939, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Case files
    - Chippewa River Power Plant (Box 4)
    - Giegler Case (Box 4)
    - Masrukewitz v. Moore (Box 4)
    - Stoflet v. Stoflet (Box 4)
  - Financial records (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous
  The Miscellaneous series contains materials relating to the legal affairs of the Moore family. Papers related to George and Katherine's divorce are located here, as are files relating to George's role as an executor of his uncle George William Moore's will.
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Divorce Material 1922-1929 (Box 4)
  - Estate of George W. Moore (uncle) 1926-1941 (Box 4)
  - Family Legal Documents 1923-1929 (Box 4)
  - William Jennings Bryan poster (Folder 1)
  - Political Cartoon of Moore by Thomas May (Folder 1)
- Ledgers
  The Ledgers series contains financial and account ledgers relating to the business dealings of Moore and Moore, the Farmers' Mutual Fire Insurance Company of Monroe and Wayne Counties, the Summit Consolidation Silver Mining Co., and the Michigan Finance Corporation, as well as George William Moore's personal financial records.
  - Directors of the Michigan Finance Corporation 1919 (Box 5)
  - Summit Consolidation Silver Mining Co. 1881-1882 (Box 5)
  - Moore & Moore Financial Ledgers 1884-1898, 4 small ledgers (Box 5)
  - Moore & Moore Financial Ledger 1921-1928 (Box 5)
  - Moore & Moore Collection Register 1902-1926 (Volume 1)
  - Personal Account Ledger 1905-1920 (Volume 2)
  - Policy Register of the Farmers' Mutual Fire Insurance Company of Monroe and Wayne Counties, MI 1921-1934 (Volume 3)